,question,Pargraphs
0,"[{'answer': 'ancient egyptian dynasties', 'question': 'What dynasties divide historians into the old kingdom, the middle kingdom, and the new kingdom?'}]","historians divide ancient egyptian dynasties into the old kingdom, the middle kingdom, and the new kingdom."
1,"[{'answer': 'sirius', 'question': 'What star appeared before the nile began to flood?'}]","about , years ago, they noticed that a star now called sirius appeared shortly before the nile began to flood."
2,"[{'answer': 'priests', 'question': 'Who studied the world to find ways to please the gods?'}]","as in many ancient societies, much of the knowledge of egypt came about as priests studied the world to find ways to please the gods."
3,"[{'answer': 'khufu', 'question': 'Who wanted a monument that would show the world how great he was?'}, {'answer': 'monument', 'question': 'What did khufu want to show the world how great he was?'}]","about  years later, a pharaoh named khufu decided he wanted a monument that would show the world how great he was."
4,"[{'answer': 'food', 'question': 'What type of items did mourners fill the tomb with?'}, {'answer': 'furniture', 'question': 'What type of items would the mummified pharaoh need?'}, {'answer': 'food', 'question': 'What type of items did mourners fill the tomb with?'}]",mourners filled the tomb with objects ranging from food to furniture that the mummified pharaoh would need.
5,"[{'answer': 'giza', 'question': 'What city was built for pyramid workers?'}, {'answer': 'pyramid workers', 'question': 'Who built giza?'}]","a city called giza was built for the pyramid workers and the people who fed, clothed, and housed them."
6,"[{'answer': 'a priest', 'question': 'Who bathed before entering a temple?'}]","before entering a temple, a priest bathed and put on special linen garments and white sandals."
7,"[{'answer': 'one of his children', 'question': 'Who took his place as ruler when a king died?'}]","when a king died, one of his children usually took his place as ruler."
8,"[{'answer': 'priests', 'question': 'Who studied the world to find ways to please the gods?'}]","as in many ancient societies, much of the knowledge of egypt came about as priests studied the world to find ways to please the gods."
9,"[{'answer': 'priests', 'question': 'Who studied the world to find ways to please the gods?'}]","as in many ancient societies, much of the knowledge of egypt came about as priests studied the world to find ways to please the gods."
10,"[{'answer': 'dug irrigation canals', 'question': 'What did river water go to dry areas?'}]","working together, they dug irrigation canals that carried river water to dry areas."
11,"[{'answer': 'valley of the kings', 'question': 'Where did pharaohs begin building more secret tombs?'}, {'answer': 'valley of the kings', 'question': 'Where did pharaohs begin building more secret tombs?'}]","during the new kingdom, pharaohs began building more secret tombs in an area called the valley of the kings."
12,"[{'answer': 'the priests and the ruler', 'question': 'Who held ceremonies to please the gods?'}]","together, the priests and the ruler held ceremonies to please the gods."
13,"[{'answer': 'blue stones', 'question': 'What type of stones were used in jewelry?'}, {'answer': 'nile', 'question': 'What type of stone had fish and other wildlife that egyptians wanted?'}]",these beautiful blue stones were used in jewelry.the nile had fish and other wildlife that egyptians wanted.
14,"[{'answer': 'a priest', 'question': 'Who bathed before entering a temple?'}]","before entering a temple, a priest bathed and put on special linen garments and white sandals."
15,"[{'answer': 'nile river', 'question': 'What river flooded every year?'}, {'answer': 'nile river', 'question': 'What river flooded every year?'}]","unlike the tigris and euphrates, the nile river flooded at the same time every year, so farmers could predict when to plant their crops."
16,"[{'answer': 'egyptian civilization', 'question': 'What kind of civilization grew more complex?'}]","as egyptian civilization grew more complex, people took on jobs other than that of a farmer or scribe."
17,"[{'answer': 'flour', 'question': 'What did the first batch of wheat grind into?'}, {'answer': 'flour', 'question': 'What did the first batch of wheat grind into?'}, {'answer': 'yeast', 'question': 'The first to grind wheat into flour and mix it with what?'}]",they were the first to grind wheat into flour and to mix the flour with yeast and water to make dough rise into bread.
18,"[{'answer': 'scribes', 'question': 'What did some ancient egyptians learn to be?'}]","for example, some ancient egyptians learned to be scribes, people whose job was to write and keep records."
19,"[{'answer': 'ropes', 'question': 'What did surveyors use to measure the land?'}]","to restore property lines, surveyors measured the land by using ropes that were knotted at regular intervals."
20,"[{'answer': 'greek historian', 'question': 'Who knew what he was talking about?'}]",the greek historian knew what he was talking about.
21,"[{'answer': 'nile river', 'question': 'What river flooded every year?'}, {'answer': 'nile river', 'question': 'What river flooded every year?'}]","unlike the tigris and euphrates, the nile river flooded at the same time every year, so farmers could predict when to plant their crops."
22,"[{'answer': 'egyptian civilization', 'question': 'What kind of civilization grew more complex?'}]","as egyptian civilization grew more complex, people took on jobs other than that of a farmer or scribe."
23,"[{'answer': 'hundreds of feet', 'question': 'How many feet did workers drag each heavy block?'}]",workers dragged each heavy block hundreds of feet and then set it in place.
24,"[{'answer': 'khufu', 'question': 'Who wanted a monument that would show the world how great he was?'}, {'answer': 'monument', 'question': 'What did khufu want to show the world how great he was?'}]","about  years later, a pharaoh named khufu decided he wanted a monument that would show the world how great he was."
25,"[{'answer': 'miles', 'question': 'How long is the longest river in the world?'}, {'answer': 'miles', 'question': 'How long is the longest river in the world?'}]","the longest river the nile is , miles longthe worlds longest river."
26,"[{'answer': 'miles', 'question': 'How long is the longest river in the world?'}, {'answer': 'miles', 'question': 'How long is the longest river in the world?'}]","the longest river the nile is , miles longthe worlds longest river."
27,"[{'answer': 'mediterranean sea', 'question': 'Where does the equator flow north to?'}]",it begins near the equator in africa and flows north to the mediterranean sea.
28,"[{'answer': 'nubia', 'question': 'What was the egyptian name for the area of the upper nile that had the richest gold mines in africa?'}]",nubia was the egyptian name for the area of the upper nile that had the richest gold mines in africa.
29,"[{'answer': 'mediterranean sea', 'question': 'Where does the equator flow north to?'}]",it begins near the equator in africa and flows north to the mediterranean sea.
30,"[{'answer': 'ibises', 'question': 'What white bird flew up from the south?'}, {'answer': 'south', 'question': 'Where did ibises fly?'}]","each year, egyptian farmers watched for white birds called ibises, which flew up from the south."
31,"[{'answer': 'south', 'question': 'Where does the nile churn with cataracts?'}, {'answer': 'nile', 'question': 'What churns with cataracts in the south?'}]",in the south the nile churns with cataracts.
32,"[{'answer': 'south', 'question': 'Where does the nile churn with cataracts?'}, {'answer': 'nile', 'question': 'What churns with cataracts in the south?'}]",in the south the nile churns with cataracts.
33,"[{'answer': 'waterfall', 'question': 'What is a cataract?'}, {'answer': 'cataract', 'question': 'What is a waterfall?'}]",a cataract is a waterfall.
34,"[{'answer': 'delta', 'question': 'Where does the nile branch into near the sea?'}, {'answer': 'near the sea', 'question': 'Where does the nile branch into a delta?'}]",near the sea the nile branches into a delta.
35,"[{'answer': 'delta', 'question': 'Where does the nile branch into near the sea?'}, {'answer': 'near the sea', 'question': 'Where does the nile branch into a delta?'}]",near the sea the nile branches into a delta.
36,"[{'answer': 'delta', 'question': 'What is an area near a rivers mouth where the water deposits fine soil called silt?'}, {'answer': 'silt', 'question': 'What is the name of a delta?'}]",a delta is an area near a rivers mouth where the water deposits fine soil called silt.
37,"[{'answer': 'valley of the kings', 'question': 'Where did pharaohs begin building more secret tombs?'}, {'answer': 'valley of the kings', 'question': 'Where did pharaohs begin building more secret tombs?'}]","during the new kingdom, pharaohs began building more secret tombs in an area called the valley of the kings."
38,"[{'answer': 'delta', 'question': 'What is an area near a rivers mouth where the water deposits fine soil called silt?'}, {'answer': 'silt', 'question': 'What is the name of a delta?'}]",a delta is an area near a rivers mouth where the water deposits fine soil called silt.
39,"[{'answer': 'great house', 'question': 'What was the word pharaoh meant?'}, {'answer': 'pharaoh', 'question': 'What word meant great house?'}]","the word pharaoh meant great house, and it was originally used to describe the kings palace."
40,"[{'answer': 'mud brick', 'question': 'What was the name of the tomb topped by the first rulers of egypt?'}, {'answer': 'underground', 'question': 'Where were the first rulers of egypt often buried?'}, {'answer': 'mud brick', 'question': 'What was the name of the tomb topped by the first rulers of egypt?'}, {'answer': 'underground', 'question': 'Where were the first rulers of egypt often buried?'}]",the first rulers of egypt were often buried in an underground tomb topped by mud brick.
41,"[{'answer': 'pyramid', 'question': 'What type of brick did the mud brick replace?'}]",they replaced the mud brick with a small pyramid of brick or stone.
42,"[{'answer': 'cities', 'question': 'What cities emerge as centers of culture and power?'}]","cities emerge as centers of culture and power, and people learn to do jobs that do not involve agriculture."
43,"[{'answer': 'black', 'question': 'What type of land did the ancient egyptians live in?'}, {'answer': 'red', 'question': 'What type of land did the ancient egyptians live in?'}]","red land, black land the ancient egyptians lived in narrow bands of land on each side of the nile."
44,"[{'answer': 'precious stones', 'question': 'What did egyptians mine?'}]",egyptians mined precious stones too.
45,"[{'answer': 'priests', 'question': 'Who cleaned the sacred statues in temples?'}]","priests cleaned the sacred statues in temples, changed their clothes, and even fed them meals."
46,"[{'answer': 'if a tomb was robbed', 'question': 'What did egyptians believe the person buried there could not have a happy afterlife?'}, {'answer': 'a happy afterlife', 'question': 'What did egyptians believe the person buried there could not have if a tomb was robbed?'}]","egyptians believed that if a tomb was robbed, the person buried there could not have a happy afterlife."
